Crafting the right message requires an in-depth understanding of your audience,
创作恰当的营销内容 需要你对其受众有深入的了解
and their needs, expectations, and behaviors.
他们的需求、期望、行为特征等等
When it comes to gathering insights about our customers,
要了解客户
there's an endless array of tools available to you.
市场上有无穷无尽的工具可供使用
This is likely one of the most saturated areas for data sources.
这大概是数据源最饱和的一个领域了
Now, before you look at the tools,
但是 在介绍具体的工具之前
let's talk specifically about what we want to measure
我们来讲一下 当我们关注受众时
within the typical insights whenever we're looking at our audience.
我们应该衡量什么或者追求什么样的洞察
I once attended a lecture that use the acronym audience to model
我以前参加了一个讲座 讲座上介绍到可以用 AUDIENCE 原则
what insights you want to capture about that audience. I'll share it with you.
来作为你了解受众的框架 我来讲一下
It starts with analysis.
首先是 A - Analysis (分析)
Who is this audience?
你的受众是谁？
Primarily, what segment or market area are we looking to capture or gather insights on?
最主要的是 我们希望了解哪些群体或者细分市场？
This could be one of our customer segments,
目标可以是某个客户群体
say that sport enthusiast or it could be one of our high value customer segments.
比如 运动爱好人士 或者 高价值客户群体
It might also be segments that we want to pursue,
也可以是我们想获取的客户群体
markets that you want to enter.
或者想进入的细分市场
For example, perhaps we want to go after people who are environmentally conscious.
比如 我们想吸引环保人士
Next, is you for understanding.
接下来是 U - Understanding (了解)
What is the audience's knowledge and attitude towards our brand?
你的受众了解你的品牌吗？对你的品牌持什么态度呢？
Do they have any familiarity with us?
他们熟悉我们的品牌吗？
We want to measure if they've been made aware of our brand,
我们想要知道他们是否已经知晓我们的品牌
and if so, how?
如果是 那么通过什么方式知晓的？
We can also measure the attitudes towards our brand typically from those who are existing
我们也可以通过已有客户群体或者曾经的客户来看看品牌评价
or past customers or we can simply look at those who talk about our brand,
或者也可以简单地看下那些提及过我们的品牌的、
but have never made any purchases.
但是未有过任何购买行为的人们
From here, we have D, for demographics.
第三个是 D - Demographics 人口统计学特征
This is all the information about your audiences age,
也就是关于你的受众的人口特征 —— 年龄、
gender, location, education, and income.
性别、位置、学历、收入
You can further refine your audience segments using your demographic variables.
你也可以结合人口特征 来进一步优化你的受众群体
For example, I can target
比如 可以是
high-income sports enthusiasts as well as targeting low income sports enthusiasts.
高收入的运动爱好人士 或者 低收入的运动爱好人士
Now, we move to I, for interest.
第四个是 I - Interest (兴趣)
What does the audience interested in?
你的受众群体对什么感兴趣？
Sure? Sports enthusiasts might add an aggregate,
当然 运动爱好人士可能是个聚合
be interested in sports in general,
普遍对运动感兴趣
but they might also have other relevant interests.
但是他们可能也有其他的相关兴趣
Lets say that 70 percent of our customer audience with
比如说 运动爱好人士里有 7 成
an affinity sports also spent a lot of time talking about fishing.
会花大量时间讨论钓鱼
Well, now we know that we have another avenue by which to engage and reach this consumer.
那么 我们也就知道其实也有另一个渠道可以触达和维持这些客户
We also need to evaluate what interests them and our brand.
我们也需要知道他们对我们的品牌的什么地方感兴趣
Why are they reading our content?
他们为什么会阅读我们的内容？
Why are they sharing it and interacting with it?
他们为什么会选择分享或者与其互动？
It's important that we understand what's motivating them.
了解这些行为背后的动力很重要
Let's move to E, for environment.
第五个是 E - Environment (环境)
Where does the audience spend time?
这些受众通常会在哪里花时间？
We need to know where to reach them.
我们需要知道通过什么渠道才能触达到他们
So if we started the environment that they're invested in,
如果我们知道他们在哪里花时间
we'll get a good idea of where we can find them and how to message to them.
我们就会知道在哪里可以找到这些受众 以及如何将消息传达给他们
Let's move to N, for needs.
第六个是 N - Needs (需求)
What does this audience need and how do we as accompany answer that need?
这些受众的需求是什么？作为一家公司 我们怎样满足他们的需求？
We might directly service that need because we have
如果我们有现成的解决方案 可以直接给他们提供服务
the solution or we simply show up in an area where they're looking for that need.
或者也可以在他们寻求解决方案的地方 曝光自己的品牌
We might simply help them find that need.
或者帮助他们发掘自己的需求
C is for customization.
第七个是 C - customization (定制)
How are we adding value?
我们提供了什么增值服务？
How do we cater and adjust our messaging?
我们如何定制或者调整自己的品牌信息？
Remember, we always want to be serving the right message to the right customer.
记住 我们的目标是用于为正确的客户提供正确的品牌信息
So we want to look for data points that give us insights into how we can speak to them.
所以 我们会希望有一些数据点 可以帮助我们了解如何定制信息
Do we need to adjust the message because this audience uses a particular style of slang?
我们是否需要做出一些调整 因为受众喜欢用某种特定风格的俚语？
Perhaps, they engage with certain types of content themes.
或者 他们会与某些特定主题的内容进行互动
We're really looking for what's in this content that they find valuable.
我们需要确保内容能对他们产生一些价值
Now finally, we have E for expectations.
最后是 E - expectations (期望)
What are both the stated and unstated expectations
对于与你的品牌互动的那些受众 他们的最明显的、“说出口”的期望是什么？
that the audience has for their interactions with your brand?
以及他们的“未说出口”的潜在期望是什么？
So we analyze all of this data to influence the aspects of our marketing strategy,
我们会分析以上所有的信息 从而影响市场决策的方方面面
and this data can come from a number of sources.
这些信息可以来源于好几处
We can pull some data from Google analytics,
首先 我们可以从 Google analytics 抓取一些数据
capturing behavior and demographic information.
比如 行为特征、人口特征
We can also model what content they're consuming and where they're finding that content,
我们也可以发现他们消费的内容类型以及在哪里找到的这些内容
which will help evaluate where there's consumer spending their time online.
这可以帮助判断消费者一般在哪里花费时间
But there's a lot more rich data for us to capture.
其实还有更多、更丰富的数据等着我们去挖掘
Native tools such as Twitter and Facebook will also reveal
获取原始数据的工具比如 Twitter 和 Facebook 可以给你提供
deep insights about your audience and
很多关于你的客户的有用信息
can answer many of the questions that we've outlined.
也可以回答我们列出的许多问题
But you also have questions that cannot be answered
但同时 我们也有一些问题 不可以单靠
simply by studying the behaviors and patterns of the segment.
行为特征和群体特征来解答
So you might want to run voice of the consumer surveys to
所以你会希望开展用户调查来
capture insights into the specific questions that you might have.
获取你的某些特定问题的答案
Surveys are a valuable source of qualitative feedback that you can tie to
调查是很有用的方式 可以获取定性反馈
analytics data to connect with what an audience says versus what it actually does.
你可以再结合分析数据 来看看客户说的和做的是否相符
Now, popular tools for this are Google surveys and SurveyMonkey.
常用调查工具包括 Google surveys 和 SurveyMonkey
Google surveys allows you to access a readily available focus group.
Google Surveys 已经提供了一些目标消费市场
You get numerous results rather
根据你希望被调查对象回答的问题
quickly based on the questions that you're hoping to answer.
你可以快速地得到很多份问卷填写
In fact, you may have seen these types of survey questions pop
事实上 如果你观看 YouTube 视频 你可能看见过这样的调查问题
up as ads before watching a YouTube video.
会在视频播放前的广告时段跳出来
Most commonly, they ask Which brands you might recognize
最常见的是它们会问你 是否见过以下品牌
or which brands that you've seen advertisements for in the last month?
以及在上个月 你看了哪个品牌的广告？
This helps accompany understand if they're reaching
这可以帮助公司判断
the audience that they're hoping to be reaching.
是否触达到了公司希望触达的人群
Now, look through each question you need to answer in
所以 可以通过 AUDIENCE 框架来回答每一个问题
the audience acronym and identify which tools you can gather that data from.
然后确定你需要使用哪些工具来抓取相关数据
For any gaps, explore the marketing tools ecosystem to find
如果出现未在本课里提及的方面 你可以通过探索市场营销工具的生态体系
a vendor that can provide that data until you
来找到一家供应商帮助你获取数据
have a complete picture of the audience you're targeting.
知道你对你的受众有了一个非常全面、彻底的了解